
/* GK Quiz Questions
 * creating an array and passing the number, questions, options, and answers
 */

let questions = [

/* Q1 */     
  {
      numb: 1,
      question: "National Income estimates in India are prepared by",
      options: [
                "A) Planning Commission",
                "B) Reserve Bank of India",
                "C) Central statistical organisation",
                "D) Indian statistical Institute"
               ],
      answer: "C) Central statistical organisation"
    },
/*Copy till here*/


/* Q2 */     
  {
      numb: 2,
      question: "The tropic of cancer does not pass through which of these Indian states?",
      options: [
                "A) Madhya Pradesh",
                "B) West Bengal",
                "C) Rajasthan",
                "D) Odisha"
               ],
      answer: "D) Odisha"
    },
/*Copy till here*/

/* Q3 */     
  {
      numb: 3,
      question: "A computer cannot 'boot' if it does not have the _____",
      options: [
                "A) Compiler",
                "B) Loader",
                "C) Operating system",
                "D) Assembler"
               ],
      answer: "C) Operating system"
    },
/*Copy till here*/
  
/* Q4 */     
  {
      numb: 4,
      question: "The purest form of iron is ",
      options: [
                "A) wrought iron",
                "B) steel",
                "C) pig iron",
                "D) nickel steel"
               ],
      answer: "A) wrought iron"
    },
/*Copy till here*/
  
/* Q5 */     
  {
      numb: 5,
      question: "The working principle of a washing machine is",
      options: [
                "A) Reverse osmosis",
                "B) Diffusion",
                "C) Centrifugation",
                "D) Dialysis"
               ],
      answer: "C) Centrifugation"
    },
/*Copy till here*/

/* Q6 */     
  {
      numb: 6,
      question: "Which river of India is called Vridha Ganga?",
      options: [
                "A) Krishna",
                "B) Godavari",
                "C) Kaveri",
                "D) Narmada"
               ],
      answer: "B) Godavari"
    },
/*Copy till here*/

/* Q7 */     
  {
      numb: 7,
      question: "________ is the process of dividing the disk into tracks and sectors",
      options: [
                "A) Tracking",
                "B) Formatting",
                "C) Crashing",
                "D) Allotting"
               ],
      answer: "B) Formatting"
    },
/*Copy till here*/

/* Q8 */ 
  {
      numb: 8,
      question: "Epsom(England) is the place associated with",
      options: [
                "A) Snooker",
                "B) Shooting",
                "C) Polo",
                "D) Horse racing"
               ],
      answer: "D) Horse racing"
    },
/*Copy till here*/

/* Q9 */ 
  {
      numb: 9,
      question: "Junk e-mail is also called ______",
      options: [
                "A) Spam",
                "B) Spoof",
                "C) Sniffer script",
                "D) Spool"
               ],
      answer: "A) Spam"
    },
/*Copy till here*/


/* Q10 */    
  {
      numb: 10,
      question: "The blue colour of the clear sky is due to",
      options: [
                "A) Diffraction of light",
                "B) Dispersion of light",
                "C) Reflection of light",
                "D) Refraction of light"
               ],
      answer: "B) Dispersion of light"
    },
/*Copy till here*/




]; /* Array close*/